Daniel Tang

Data Scientist

Portfolio: https://dtang29.github.io/

San Jose, CA T: +1.415.539.5369 E: daniel.tang1529@gmail.com

Summary

Recently transitioned Data analyst to Data Scientist with 6+ years working in the data analytics field with strong technical background. Currently have a strong interest transitioning to an engineering role with emphasis in data integration and pipeline work.

Technical Skills

Languages → SQL, Python, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Google Apps Script

Data Visualization → Tableau, Google PLX, Google Data Studio, D3, Leaflet, Plotly, Matplotlib

Data Mining/Wrangling → API Interactions, Web Scraping (Beautiful Soup, Selenium)

Databases → Presto, Hive, MySQL, Sqlite

Pipeline Workflow → uWorc, Airflow

Version Control → Github

Experience

Uber, Safety Support

San Francisco, CA and San Jose, CA

Data Scientist II Data Analyst II Data Analyst I 2021-11 to Present 2020-03 to 2021-11 2019-01 to 2020-03

- Main Analytics & Insights (A&I) POC for Global Safety Support Program, worked with regional partners to ensure all reported KPIs are globally standardized and aligned
- Launched the first set of data tables for safety support program that is now the main source of truth for all safety support KPIs reported in monthly MBRs (uWorc); Maintained scheduled pipelines (Piper) for safety program and ensuring data is readily available for regional analysts to utilize
- Built dashboards (Tableau/Google Data Studio) utilizing different data sources, working with different SQL databases and warehouses ranging from Presto to Hive to BigQuery
- Utilized Python to connect to the google sheets and querybuilder API to automate data pulls for scorecard reporting

Google Payments (Vaco), Business Operations

Mountain View, CA

2018-02 to 2019-01

Business Analyst

- Maintained, created dashboards; monitored pipeline that fed data into high traffic usage dashboards
- Addressed priority bugs within our bug queue workflow (buganizer); Pulled ad-hoc analyses for product managers, analysts, specialists, etc utilizing SQL based language (GoogleSQL)
- Performed QA tests to validate accuracy of data metrics during a transition of our primary transactions table in Q2 to include new relevant fields with better naming conventions
- Assisted on a project to improve the machine learning algorithm to identify users with good payment history, leading to a 3% improvement

Youtube (Vaco), Trust & Safety

San Bruno, CA

Business Analyst

2017-04 to 2018-02

- Supported Operation Managers with metrics gathering and slide creations for their business reviews that was presented to Youtube stakeholders
- Met with Vaco Leads and Managers weekly to gather requirements around changes in priority of the product/workflows
- Developed new Vaco onboarding/tracking process and manager tools which successfully increased managers' bandwidth

Education

Udacity

Data Engineering Nanodegree, 2020

University of California, Berkeley Extension

Certificate, Data Analysis & Visualization, 2018-02 to 2018-08

Part time Data Analysis & Visualization Bootcamp by UC Berkeley Extension Program

University of California, Davis

Bachelor of Science in Managerial Economics/Business, Graduated Fall 2015